hi everybody welcome back to the channel
I'm Nick today we are doing
a valrona chocolate using the cocoa
powder the caramelia chocolate and their
praline so if you want to see what we do
with it stick around and we'll show you
so valrona posted a recipe on Instagram
of how to make this
I don't know like spread it's like a
praline hazelnut almond spread almost to
better Nutella
and it was amazing
Tip Tap top I made this
that was me and clipping the whatever
I made this stuff and the smell is out
this world and the taste is just
incredible I mean we've eaten half this
tub just on a spoon
and as I've got all over my face
I thought
we've got these ingredients
that we bought using supporters funds on
Kofi
put a little link on screen here if you
want to support the channel be really
really helpful
we bought the chocolate the cocoa powder
and the praline and what we didn't use
in making that spread
I thought we'd use in an ice cream so we
went all valrona and made a faroner
chocolate base
with the praline swirled throughout
caramina caramelia chocolate pieces in
there as well so how do we do it
so the actual ice cream base for this
valrona
spectacular let's call it that it's
quite simple it starts with your milk as
always and to that we're going to add in
our sucrose and our dextrose get those
completely dissolved into your milk and
then when you're about 50 to 60 degrees
add in your cocoa powder and your milk
powder and then make sure they're
completely homogenized
take it off the heat put it in a
container add in your cream give it one
final really good stir and then pop it
in a fridge to chill down for a few
hours
once it's completely chilled you can
take it out of the fridge give it a
final stir just to make sure it's ready
to go and then pop it in your machine to
churn whilst it's churning you're going
to take your caramelia chocolate chop it
up into nice small pieces put it in the
container because we're gonna put that
in the ice cream in a minute
there you can see we've got our tub of
praline sitting already on the side and
once your ice cream is ready and you're
right at the last minute of churning add
in your caramelia chocolate and now we
can start loading at the top so you're
just going to take some of your ice
cream put it in the container and start
swirling your praline throughout just
load up the tubs completely put them in
the freezer to chill down for a few
hours
foreign
[Music]
has been in the freezer for
ages ages probably what close to two
months
by the time I've got around to filming
this part of the video so
I'm looking forward to trying it let's
get some scooped up in a bowl see what
it ended up like
[Music]
foreign
not to dive in I normally try a bit of
the ice cream when it gets dished up you
know even if it's just the base itself
rather than the whole mix
but I didn't with this one so really
looking forward to this it smells great
let's see what it tastes like
oh
that's a good ice cream now if you've
ever used Barona cocoa before you know
it has a slightly different effect
than most cocoa powders adds a fudginess
I don't know why
um
so it's quite unique and it has this
really strong intense but not overly
bitter flavor which is really nice
and that's what you've got here you've
got this very rich decadent chocolate
ice cream that's not so strong that it
overtakes flavors of everything else
you got a small little texture change
with the little pieces of the caramelia
chocolate in there
which is milk chocolate 36 but with this
underlying caramel flavor to it
and then
you've got this praline
try and
dig some out it's kind of left a ribbon
you can't really see it I'll just eat it
just left this ribbon
of
nutty
it's like super soft caramel
such a nice flavor change to that rich
chocolate ice cream
I mean it's a pricey this is a price you
make you know this this praline was 13
pounds for 300 gram tub you know the
chocolate I think was like 11 or 12
pounds and this little 250 gram tub
cocoa powder is also around 10 to 12
pounds you're obviously not using all of
the ingredients in here you're just
using part of it but you've still got to
buy the ingredients anyway in the first
place so but if you're if you've got a
nice evening meal or a dinner planned
and you've got some chocolate ice cream
fans definitely try this one I think
you're going to please most people with
this even if they're not chocolate fans
you can't really not like this one it's
really really good so
again really thankful to our supporters
on Kofi that enabled us to use buy these
ingredients when we ordinarily wouldn't
be able to
hopefully we've done them Justice with
creating this and as always thanks very
much don't forget to like And subscribe
70 of our Watchers aren't subscribed and
we'll see you next week
[Music]